Margaret Henderson Floyd Architectural Slide Collection MS175
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Margaret Henderson Floyd Architectural Slide Collection
1955 -- 1998
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Floyd, Margaret H.
MS175
16.0 Linear Feet 40 boxes
Arrangement
This collection has one series.
Custodial History
In the fall of 2010, the Art History Department transferred 40 binders to DCA. These binders contained slides that Margaret Henderson Floyd (1932-1997) had used for teaching (see collection documentation for more information). After her death, Floyd's family transferred the forty binders to the Art History Department at Tufts (transfer date unclear).
Since that time, many slides were removed from the binders for use in classroom teaching and were then filed in the overall slide collection of the Art History Department where they still remain to this day. Therefore, many/most binder slide pockets were empty when transferred to DCA. Because the Art History Department's Access database is not functioning as of January 2011, Floyd slides that were integrated into the department's overall slide collection cannot be identified. DCA was therefore unable to restore the binders' original content. In addition, Floyd's original order and labeling cannot be reconstructed: the numerical order (number 1-40) of the binders and many labels and lists were created after her death.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, photographs, postcards, slide inventories, slides, and travel itinerary notes. Materials in this collection are dated from 1955 to 1998. Professor Margaret Henderson Floyd used these slides in classroom instruction and for her research: they depict buildings, rooms, architects, terra cotta items, sculptures, and paintings from the United States, Central America, and Europe (such as England, Germany, and Italy). These slides also depict images from various books.
Biographical / Historical
Margaret Henderson Floyd (1932-1997) was a professor in the Department of Art and Art History at Tufts University from 1977 until 1997.
Born in New York City, Floyd graduated from Wellesley College with a BA in Art History in 1953. She went on to receive a master's degree in Art History from the University of New Mexico in 1957, and earned her Ph.D. in American Studies from Boston University in 1974.
At Tufts, Floyd taught courses on architectural history and American art. One of her most popular courses focused on Boston and Cambridge architecture. In 1981, Floyd was appointed to the Campus Planning and Development Committee by Dean Frank Colcord. In 1983, she began work on an architectural inventory of university buildings for the committee. She also served as chair of the Fine Arts Department from 1983 to 1987, when she was involved in establishing Tufts University Art Gallery.
Floyd gave frequent walking tours of Boston, and an annual architectural tour of Newport, R.I. mansions. She was active in local historic preservation projects and involved with the Boston Architectural Center. Her published works include Harvard: An Architectural History (co-authored with Bainbridge Bunting, 1985); Architectural Education and Boston (1989); Architecture after Richardson: Regionalism before Modernism--Longfellow, Alden, and Harlow in Boston and Pittsburgh (1994); and Henry Hobson Richardson: A Genius for Architecture (1997).
Margaret Henderson Floyd died of cancer on October 18, 1997. The Department of Art and Art History established the Margaret Henderson Floyd Memorial Lecture (1999) and the Architectural Studies Prize (2006) in her honor.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Architecture; Faculty research
- Architectural slides, 1955 -- 1998; 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001; 16.0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains 40 boxes. Each box contains the slides of one slide binder transferred to DCA in the fall of 2010. Most slides are not dated: the date range is approximate.
  Professor Margaret Henderson Floyd used these slides in the classroom and for her research. They were either bought commercially (usually indicated on the frame) or were taken by Floyd and others. Because the photographers are usually not identified on individual slides, copyright will be a major issue for this collection.
  Slides depict buildings, rooms, and architects but also terra cotta items, sculptures and paintings from the United States, Central America, and Europe as well as reproductions from books such as architectural drawings or portraits (most books are not clearly identified); also included are a few photographs, post cards, some correspondence and travel itinerary notes.
  See processing notes for provenance, original order, and decisions regarding labeling the collection.
  Arrangement
  This series is organized primarily by geography and as maintained by the Art History Department: slides about architectural sites labeled US Geography (alphabetical by states) are followed by Massachusetts Geography (alphabetical by cities), followed by US Architects (alphabetical by last name), followed by boxes dedicated to individual architects (alphabetical by name), followed by architectural sites labeled 'English Geography' (alphabetical by location), English Architect (alphabetical by last name), 'German Geography,' 'German Architects,' 'Central American, South American, US, and Spanish architecture,' a box of 'Terra Cotta' slides, a box of 'Painting and Sculpture' slides, and a box of 'Colling' slides.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - US geography, 1955 -- 1997; MS175.001.001
    - Inventory, 1997; MS175.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
      Hunt, Richard Morris, 1828-1895
    - Arizona, 1983; MS175.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    - California Hearst Castle, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    - Los Angeles, California, 1978; MS175.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    - Oakland, California, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    - Hartford, CT, 1967 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    - Old Lyme, CT, 1978; MS175.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    - Rowaton, CT, 1972; MS175.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    - Rowaton, CT, 1972; MS175.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    - Southbridge, CT, 1978; MS175.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    - Stamford, CT, 1967; MS175.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
    - Talcottville, CT, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    - Washington, DC, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
    - Athens, GA, 1974; MS175.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
    - Atlanta, GA 1, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
    - Atlanta, GA 2, 1969; MS175.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
    - Greenville, GA, 1965; MS175.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
    - Stone Mt., GA, 1966; MS175.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    - Chicago, IL, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
    - Pullman, IL, 1971; MS175.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
    - Casco, ME, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
    - Oxford, ME, 1966; MS175.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
    - Portland, ME, 1968 -- 1983; MS175.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
    - Vienna, ME, 1967; MS175.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
    - Annapolis, MD, 1978; MS175.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
    - Baltimore, MD 1, 1970; MS175.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
    - Baltimore, MD 2, 1970; MS175.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
    - Inventory, 1997; MS175.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    - St. Paul, MN #1, 1975; MS175.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    - St. Paul, MN #2, 1975; MS175.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    - Independence, MO, 1970; MS175.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
    - Kansas City, MO, 1970; MS175.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
    - Concord, NH, 1970; MS175.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
    - Derry, NH, 1971; MS175.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
    - Laconia, NH, 1970; MS175.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
    - Manchester, NH, 1972; MS175.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
    - New London, NH, 1972; MS175.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
    - Penacook, NH, 1972; MS175.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
    - Peterborough, NH, 1972; MS175.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
    - Tilton, NH, 1972; MS175.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
    - Berrytown, NY, 1971; MS175.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
    - Casco, ME, 1971; MS175.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
    - Claverack, NY, 1971; MS175.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
    - Clermont, NY, 1971; MS175.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
    - Fordham, NY, 1971; MS175.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
    - Garrison-on-Hudson, NY, 1971; MS175.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
    - Genesco, NY, 1974; MS175.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
    - Hyde Park, NY, 1971; MS175.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
    - Ithaca, NY 1, 1978; MS175.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
    - Ithaca, NY 2, 1978; MS175.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
    - Ithaca, NY 3/ town, 1978; MS175.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
    - Mellenville, NY, 1978; MS175.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
    - New York City, NY, 1970; MS175.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
    - Red Hook, NY, 1971; MS175.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
    - Rochester, NY 1, 1971; MS175.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
    - Rochester, NY 2, 1971; MS175.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
    - Roslyn, NY, 1970; MS175.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
    - Inventory, 1997; MS175.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
    - Philadelphia, PA 1, 1970 -- 1978; MS175.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
    - Philadelphia, PA 2, 1970 -- 1981; MS175.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
    - Pittsburgh, PA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
    - Barrington, RI, 1975; MS175.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
    - Newport, RI 1, 1994; MS175.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
    - Newport, RI 2, 1968 -- 1972; MS175.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
    - Providence, RI, 1973 -- 1974; MS175.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
    - Dallas, TX, 1958 -- 1968; MS175.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
    - El Paso, TX, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
    - San Antonio, TX 1, 1978; MS175.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
    - San Antonio, TX 2, 1978; MS175.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
    - Salt Lake City, UT, 1955 -- 1972; MS175.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
    - Montpelier, VT 1, 1966 -- 1972; MS175.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
    - Montpelier, VT 2, 1966 -- 1972; MS175.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
    - Queechee, VT, 1975; MS175.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
    - James City County, VA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
    - Richmond, VA, 1974; MS175.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
    - Surrey County, VA, 1970 -- 1994; MS175.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
    - Wight County, VA, 1978; MS175.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
    - Williamsburg, VA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
    - Seattle, WA [1], 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
    - Seattle, WA [2], 1995; MS175.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
    - Washington, D.C., 1973 -- 1976; MS175.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
    - Silos, 1956; MS175.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
      Silos
  - Slide binder, 1960 -- 1997; MS175.001.002
    - Inventory, 1997; MS175.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
    - General, MA, 1978; MS175.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
    - Amesbury, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
    - Berlin, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
    - Brockton, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
    - Brookfield, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Aspinwall, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Coolidge Corner, 1988; MS175.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Coolidge Corner, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Country Club Area, 1975 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Linden, 1978 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Longwood Area, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Pill Hill, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA The Point, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Town Green Area, 1978 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA Town Green Area, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA The Village, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA White Place, 1978 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
    - Brookline, MA White Place, 1978; MS175.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
    - Cohasset, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
    - Cambridge, MA, 1964 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00022 (Box 4)
    - Concord, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.004.00023 (Box 4)
    - Dedham, MA, 1981; MS175.001.004.00024 (Box 4)
    - Inventory, 1997; MS175.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
    - Fairhaven, MA, 1969; MS175.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
    - Framingham, MA #1, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
    - Framingham, MA #2, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
    - Gloucester, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
    - Hingham, MA, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
    - Lee, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
    - Lexington, MA, 1966; MS175.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
    - Lincoln, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
    - Lowell, MA, 1982 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
    - Manchester, MA, 1968 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
    - Marblehead, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
    - Medford, MA, 1983 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
    - Methuen, MA, 1971 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
    - New Bedford, MA, 1983; MS175.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
    - New Bedford, MA, 1983 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
    - Newton, MA #1, 1965 -- 1968; MS175.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
    - Newton, MA #2, 1965 -- 1968; MS175.001.005.00018 (Box 5)
    - North Easton, MA, 1972; MS175.001.005.00019 (Box 5)
    - North Hampton, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00020 (Box 5)
    - Oak Bluffs, MA, 1974 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00021 (Box 5)
    - Petersham, MA, 1974; MS175.001.005.00022 (Box 5)
    - Plymouth, MA, 1966 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00023 (Box 5)
    - Princeton, MA, 1966 -- 1997; MS175.001.005.00024 (Box 5)
    - Inventory, MS175.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
    - General, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
    - Andrew, J./Baldwin/Anderson, 1991; MS175.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
      Andrew, John; Baldwin, Ned; Anderson, Robert
    - Bryant/Gilman, 1974; MS175.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
      Bryant, Gridley James Fox; Gilman, Arthur Delavan
    - Coolidge/others, 1977 -- 1991; MS175.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
      Coolidge, Cornelius
    - Gropius/Gund, 1974 -- 1990; MS175.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
      Gropius, Walter; Gund, Graham
    - Kilham/Hopkins/Lowell, Guy, 1977 -- 1990; MS175.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
      Kilham, Walter Harrington; Hopkins, James C.; Lowell, Guy
    - McGinnis/Walsh/McKin/others, 1976 -- 1990; MS175.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
      Maginnis, Charles Donagh; Walsh, Timothy; McKim, Charles Follen
    - Schulze, Paul, 1972; MS175.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
      Schulze, Paul
    - Shaw/Hunnewall, 1974; MS175.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
      Shaw, George Russell; Hunnewell, Hollis
    - Sert, J. L., 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
      Sert, Josep Lluis
    - Shepley/others, 1974 -- 1990; MS175.001.008.00012 (Box 8)
      Shepley, George Foster
    - Smibert, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.008.00013 (Box 8)
      Smibert, John
    - Sterling, James [1], 1991; MS175.001.008.00014 (Box 8)
      Sterling, James
    - Sterling, James [2], 1991; MS175.001.008.00015 (Box 8)
    - Sterling, James [3], 1991; MS175.001.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - US geography: Massachusetts, 1965 -- 1998; MS175.001.003
    - Inventory, 1970 -- 1998; MS175.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
    - Salem, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
    - Salem, MA, 1972 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
    - Salem, MA, 1975 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
    - Southbridge, MA, 1975; MS175.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
    - Springfield, MA, 1973 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
    - Stockbridge, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
    - Sudbury, MA 1, 1966 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
    - Sudbury, MA 2, 1966; MS175.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
    - Waltham, MA 1, 1966 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
    - Waltham, MA 2, 1966 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
    - Waltham, MA 3, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00012 (Box 6)
    - Waltham, MA 4, 1968; MS175.001.006.00013 (Box 6)
    - Wayland, MA, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00014 (Box 6)
    - Wellesley, MA 1, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00015 (Box 6)
    - Wellesley, MA 2, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00016 (Box 6)
    - Weston, MA 1, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00017 (Box 6)
    - Weston, MA 2, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00018 (Box 6)
    - Woburn, MA, 1966; MS175.001.006.00019 (Box 6)
    - Worcester, MA, 1975 -- 1997; MS175.001.006.00020 (Box 6)
  - Massachusetts geography: Boston, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.004
    - Inventory, 1997; MS175.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
    - White Hill/Martha J. Lamb, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
    - EC Porter rambles in Old Boston, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
    - Views of Boston, 1965 -- 1994; MS175.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
    - Boston, MA, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
    - Boston, 1983; MS175.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
    - Boston Ashmont Hill 1, 1972; MS175.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
    - Boston Ashmont Hill 2, 1972; MS175.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
    - Boston Ashmont Hill 3, 1972; MS175.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
    - Boston Ashmont Hill 4, 1972; MS175.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
    - Boston Back Bay, 1969 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
    - Boston Beacon Hill, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
    - Dorchester, 1991; MS175.001.007.00013 (Box 7)
    - Fenway, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00014 (Box 7)
    - Boston Government Center, 1968 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00015 (Box 7)
    - Boston Jamaica Plain, 1968; MS175.001.007.00016 (Box 7)
    - Boston North End, 1973 -- 1993; MS175.001.007.00017 (Box 7)
    - Boston Roxbury, 1973; MS175.001.007.00018 (Box 7)
    - Boston South End, 1965; MS175.001.007.00019 (Box 7)
    - Boston Waterfront, 1973 -- 1997; MS175.001.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - US architects, 1960 -- 1997; MS175.001.005
    - Inventory, MS175.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
    - Allen and Collens/The Cloisters NYC, 1962; MS175.001.009.00002 (Box 9)
      Allen and Collens
    - Allen and Kenway, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.009.00003 (Box 9)
      Allen and Kenway
    - H. Austin/Grove Street Cemetery/Morse-Libby Hse, 1968 -- 1975; MS175.001.009.00004 (Box 9)
      Henry Austin
    - Henry Austin #2/Morse-Libby Portland, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.009.00005 (Box 9)
    - P. Banner, 1965; MS175.001.009.00006 (Box 9)
      Banner, P.
    - Asher Benjamin, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.009.00007 (Box 9)
      Benjamin, Asher
    - E. Boyden/Mechanics Hall Worchester, MA, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.009.00008 (Box 9)
      Boyden, Eldridge
    - J. Brady/St. Luke's Epicopal Ch., 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.009.00009 (Box 9)
      Brady, Josiah R.
    - Bryant and Gilman/See also Harvard U./Charles St. Jail- Boston, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.009.00010 (Box 9)
      Bryant, Gridley James Fox
    - Wm. Buckland/Hammon-Harwood, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.009.00011 (Box 9)
      Buckland, William
    - C. Bulfinch #1/H.O.G House 1806 #3/45 Beacon St., 1965 -- 1974; MS175.001.009.00012 (Box 9)
      Bulfinch, Charles
    - C. Bulfinch #2/Faneull Hall/University Hall, Harvard/Boston State House, 1965 -- 1973; MS175.001.009.00013 (Box 9)
    - Burnham, Daniel/Filene's Boston, 1983 -- 1984; MS175.001.009.00014 (Box 9)
    - E.C. Cabot/Boston Athenaeum, 1961 -- 1972; MS175.001.009.00015 (Box 9)
    - Ogden and Codman, 1994; MS175.001.009.00016 (Box 9)
    - R.A. Cram #1/Cambridge Monastery/Sudbury Cram Chapel, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.009.00017 (Box 9)
    - R.A. Cram #2/All Saints Peterborough/Cram's Grane, 1976; MS175.001.009.00018 (Box 9)
    - R.A. Cram #2/2nd Unitarian Church, 1982; MS175.001.009.00019 (Box 9)
    - R.A. Cram, 1982; MS175.001.009.00020 (Box 9)
    - Cummings and Sears/New Old South Church, 1964 -- 1977; MS175.001.009.00021 (Box 9)
    - Cummings and Sears, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.009.00022 (Box 9)
    - Cummings and Sears, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.009.00023 (Box 9)
    - Cummings and Sears, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.009.00024 (Box 9)
    - Cummings and Sears, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.009.00025 (Box 9)
    - Inventory, 1996; MS175.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
    - A.J. Davis / Lyndhurst / H. Delamater House / US Customs House, NY, 1971 -- 1973; MS175.001.010.00002 (Box 10)
      Davis, Alexander Jackson
    - A.J. Davis / A.J. Downing / Sunnyside, Tarrytown, NY / Queset House, 1971 -- 1973; MS175.001.010.00003 (Box 10)
      Davis, Alexander Jackson; Downing, A. J. (Andrew Jackson)
    - E. Dow / St. Paul's Church, Concord, NH, 1976 -- 1978; MS175.001.010.00004 (Box 10)
      Dow, Edward
    - S. Earle #1 / Whitcomb House, Worcester, 1976; MS175.001.010.00005 (Box 10)
      Earle, Stephen Carpenter
    - S. Earle #2, 1975 -- 1976; MS175.001.010.00006 (Box 10)
    - Ch. Eidlitz / The Chalet, Newport RI, 1972; MS175.001.010.00007 (Box 10)
      Eidlitz, Leopold
    - W.R. Emerson / Boston Art Club / Loring House, Beverly, 1972 -- 1977; MS175.001.010.00008 (Box 10)
      Emerson, William Ralph
    - W.R. Emerson #2 / W.R. Emerson House, Milton, 1972; MS175.001.010.00009 (Box 10)
    - J.L. Faxon / Victoria Hotel, 1977 -- 1983; MS175.001.010.00010 (Box 10)
      Faxon, John Layman
    - F. Furness / Pa. Academy of Fine Arts, 1970; MS175.001.010.00011 (Box 10)
      Furness, Frank
    - Arthur Gilman / Hunnewell / Sears Chapel, 1975; MS175.001.010.00012 (Box 10)
      Gilman, Arthur
    - Bertram Goodhue, 1985 -- 1989; MS175.001.010.00013 (Box 10)
      Goodhue, Bertram Grosvenor
    - Greene / Cathedral of St. John, 1976; MS175.001.010.00014 (Box 10)
      Greene, J.H.
    - Inventory, 1996; MS175.001.011.00001 (Box 11)
    - John Hamilton/ Westminster Presb. Church Columbus, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00002 (Box 12)
      Hamilton, John R.
    - Peter Harrison, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00003 (Box 11)
      Harrison, Peter, 1716-1775
    - Hartwell and Richardson #1, MS175.001.011.00004 (Box 11)
      Hartwell & Richardson
    - Hartwell and Richardson # 2, 1965 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00005 (Box 11)
    - Arthur Holden/ Holden House, 1967 -- 1981; MS175.001.011.00006 (Box 11)
      Holden, Arthur Cort, 1890-
    - Philip Hooker- Albany, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00007 (Box 11)
      Hooker, Philip; Meier, Richard, 1934-
    - Jefferson, Thomas/ Monticello, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00008 (Box 11)
      Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    - Johnson, Philip/ see also Boston Public Library addition, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00009 (Box 11)
      Johnson, Philip
    - Keller, 1984; MS175.001.011.00010 (Box 11)
      Keller, George, 1852-1935
    - Kimball, Francis/ Day House, Hartford CT, 1974 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00011 (Box 11)
      Kimball, Francis
    - Kimball, Francis #2/ Montauk Club, Brooklyn, 1982; MS175.001.011.00012 (Box 11)
    - Kimball, Francis #3, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00013 (Box 11)
    - Latrobe, Benjamin/ Baltimore Cathedral, 1970 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00014 (Box 11)
      Latrobe, Benjamin
    - D. Lienan/ Lookwood-Matthews Hse 1864, 1972; MS175.001.011.00015 (Box 11)
      Lienan, Detlef
    - Arthur Little/ Emerton House Salem/ Cliffs, Manchester, MA, 1972 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00016 (Box 11)
      Little, Arthur
    - C. Luce/ Shaw House, 1967 -- 1997; MS175.001.011.00017 (Box 11)
      Luce, Clarence S.
    - Inventory, 1996; MS175.001.012.00001 (Box 12)
    - Mason, George C., 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00002 (Box 12)
      Mason, George C
    - McArthur, James, 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00003 (Box 12)
      McArthur, James
    - McIntire, Samuel/The Vale [1], 1966 -- 1977; MS175.001.012.00004 (Box 12)
      McIntire, Samuel
    - McIntire, Samuel\The Vale [2], 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00005 (Box 12)
    - McKim/Mead/White [1], 1960 -- 1994; MS175.001.012.00006 (Box 12)
      McKim, Charles Follen; Mead, William Rutherford; White, Stanford
    - McKim/Mead/White [2], 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00007 (Box 12)
    - McKim/Mead/White [3], 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00008 (Box 12)
    - McKim/Mead/White [4], 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00009 (Box 12)
    - McKim/Mead/White [5], 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00010 (Box 12)
    - McKim/Mead/White [6], 1960 -- 1990; MS175.001.012.00011 (Box 12)